Guide to the Glenn Washington Herrick papers, 1872-1963.
Herrick, Glenn Washington papers, 1972-1963.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Glenn Washington Herrick papers, 1872-1963.
21-23-844
Glenn W. (Glenn Washington) Herrick, 1870-1965.
5.2 cubic ft.
Scientific addresses, lecture notes, articles, bulletins, drawing and illustrations.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Scientific addresses; lecture notes on spiders; articles and bulletins; page proofs and original drawings and illustrations for Insect Enemies of Shade Trees; bibliographies; lists of students and alumni; scientific drawings and photographs; diaries; correspondence concerning the Cornell Department of Entomology; travel papers; personal accounts; newspaper clippings; outline talks and short manuscript writings on politics, education, the Cornell campus, and the Cornell Entomology Department; an oral history; photograph of Jugatae members; personal letters written to Glenn and Nannie Herrick; and genealogical material and family correspondence.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of entomology, Cornell University.
Cornell University Class of 1896.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Scientific addresses; lecture notes on spiders; articles and bulletins; page proofs and original drawings and illustrations for Insect Enemies of Shade Trees; bibliographies; lists of students and alumni; scientific drawings and photographs; diaries; correspondence concerning the Cornell Department of Entomology; travel papers; personal accounts; newspaper clippings; outline talks and short manuscript writings on politics, education, the Cornell campus, and the Cornell Entomology Department; an oral history; photograph of Jugatae members; personal letters written to Glenn and Nannie Herrick; and genealogical material and family correspondence.
Includes a letter to Herrick from George Lincoln Burr with suggestions for the Comstocks of Cornell manuscript, written from Philadelphia, 12 April 1938.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Herrick, Glenn Washington, 1870-1965.; Herrick family.; Herrick, Nannie.; Cornell University; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University. Entomology Dept.; Jugatae.
Subjects:
Education.; Entomology.; Insects.; Politics, Practical.; Spiders.; College teachers.; Entomologists.
Form and Genre Terms:
Bibliographies.; Drawings.; Genealogies.; Lecture notes.; Oral histories.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 52 pcs., Dec. 17, 1921-Aug. 14, 1963, and n.d. (Box 1)
- Genealogy, 11 pcs. (Box 1)
  Includes correspondence with Burke's Landed Gentry, Apr. 13, 1938-July 21, 1939; letter from Institute of American Genealogy (Apr. 27, 1939); certificate of merit in genealogy; Herrick family genealogy, compiled by Media Research Bureau, Washington, D.C.
- Newspaper clippings, 25 pcs., Aug. 20, 1924-Oct. 7, 1953, and n.d. (Box 1)
- Photographs, 14 pcs. (Box 1)
  Includes Parkenham Gardens (in Charlemette [?]); Sao-Ke Alfred Sze, with an article about him pasted on the back; "Ed" at 18 yrs. (1922); "Burky"; G.W. Herrick, 1962; 7 unidentified pcs. Also (outside the folder), a photo of Fourth International Congress of Entomology, 1928; framed photograph of Andrew Dickson White (framed, signed photo Herrick placed in biographical file).
- Certificates, 13 pcs. (Box 1)
  Various certificates of membership, etc. Includes 2 copies of Faculty Testimonial at Herrick's retirement from Cornell, 1936.
- Papers concerning retirement, 53 pcs., 3 items, June 16, 1920-Jan. 7, 1947, and n.d. (Box 1)
- Scientific drawings and photographs, 25 pcs. (Box 2)
- Galerucella cavicollis (?) 2nd stage (Box 2)
- Agricultural ant nest (Box 2)
- American Syrphus-fly (Box 2)
- 1 folder containing three pcs. labelled as probably pine-bark aphid (Box 2)
- 19 unidentified pieces (Box 2)
- Scientific addresses, 90 pcs.: (Box 3)
  - "Concerning the Proposed Quarantine Against the Mediterranean Fruit Fly," 8 pp.
  - "Concerning Quarantines Against the Japanese Beetle," 10 pp.
  - "Some Economic Aspects of the Plant Quarantine," 52 pp. (5 copies, all varying somewhat)
  - "Concerning the Removal of Federal Domestic Quarantines on the European Corn Borer and Japanese Beetle and of the Certification of Narcissus Bulbs for Interstate Shipment," 4 pp. (2 copies)
  - "The Economics of Insect Quarantines," 12 pp.
  - "The Procession of Introduced Pests," 4 pp. (2 copies)
- Scientific abstract, made by Herrick: "Transportation of the Alfalfa Weevil by Railway Cars," by George I. Reeves, U.S. Bureau of Entomology (Box 3)
- Typed historical sketches, 11 pcs. (Box 3)
  "Simon Henry Gage," incomplete biographical sketch, 3 pp.
  Brief biographical sketch of Gage, 1 p.
  "The Story of the Entomological Department as Told by the Cornell Register," 7 pp.
- Entomology Course 3 and 4 Spider Lecture (with assorted notes in folder) (Box 3)
- Folder of "Outline Talks" in various scientific and non-scientific topics (an index on binding of folder) (Box 3)
- Scientific journals, articles, and C.U. scientific bulletins, 57 items, Nov. 1910-Oct. 1948 and n.d. (Box 4)
  Includes Herrick's "Plantations" writing (Summer 1946-Summer 1953)
- Verifax bibliog. of Herrick's works, 1901-1938 (Box 4)
- Proofs and corrected pages of Insect Enemies of Shade Trees, by Herrick, 1935 (Box 4)
- Pamphlets, on non-scientific subjects, 32 items, 1872-Oct. 1949, and n.d. (Box 5)
- Travel, 66 items, 122 pcs.: (Box 6)
  - 66 pamphlets and brochures
  - 22 maps
  - 1 pc. of sheet music ("My Louisiana")
  - Affidavit for passport, attested to by Anna Botsford Comstock, 1925
  - Correspondence concerning travel, 12 pcs., Jan. 28, 1939-Nov. 29, 1950
  - 2 blank postcards
  - Notes about travels or itineraries, 84 hand- or typewritten sheets
- Accounts (sheets of accounts tied together); 18 items, 1917-1934 (Box 7A)
- Checkbook, 1943 (Box 7A)
- Back of account book with poem pasted in (Box 7A)
- Bills, 67 pcs., Mar. 26-Sept. 4, 1934, and n.d. (Box 7A)
- Account books, 14 items, 1930-1943 (Box 7A)
- Account books, 20 items, 1944-1963 (Box 7B)
- Theater, concert, and misc. programs, 46 items, 6 pcs., Nov. 1922-Aug. 18, 1928, and n.d. (Box 8)
- Books: (Box 8)
  - Bible ("Nannie Burke" printed on cover), 1888
  - Selections from the Latin Poets, 1891
  - Two copies of Class of '96 book, Cornell
  - Ten-year book of Quill and Dagger Society
  - Common Prayer Book, 1907
- Misc. manuscripts, 15 pcs.: (Box 9)
  - Poems
  - Typed papers on various topics
  - Some drafts of letters Herrick sent to newspapers
  - Excerpt from Reader's Digest
- Names and addresses, 2 items (Box 9)
  Names and addresses mostly on index cards
  Mimeographed list of names and addresses of alumni of Cornell Entomological Department
- Two logs and two passenger lists from ship "Orduna" (Box 9)
- Autograph book (Herrick), 1888 (Box 9)
- Class of '96 button (Box 9)
- Academic robe material samples (Box 9)
- List of MA's and PhD's granted, 1926-1930 (Box 9)
- Postcard booklet (Cornell University pictures) (Box 9)
- 5 pcs. pertaining to Glenn's home in Cayuga Heights (Box 9)
- Big Red Cheers, 1 pc. (Box 9)
- Paper accompanying first issue of commemorative stamp - Michigan State U. (Box 9)
- 1942 Report of Jacob Riis Neighborhood House, N.Y.C. (Box 9)
- Menu - R.M.S.P. "Orca", Sept. 3, 1926 (Box 9)
- Original illustrations for Insect Enemies of Shade Trees; 28 folders, frontispiece and figures 1-321; numbers 240, 241 are missing (Box 11)
- Diaries, 6 items, 1938-1940, 1955-1959 (Box 12)
- Diaries, 3 items, 1960-1962 (Box 13)
- Correspondence files A-W, special, 1930-1931 (Box 14)
- Oral history (copy), 1963 (Box 15)
- Cornell items (Box 15)
- Letters to the Herricks (Box 15)
- Photographs (Box 15)